Finding Aid for Joe Louis scrapbooks and papers, 1935-1941 and 1948-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Joe Louis scrapbooks and papers 1935-1941 1948-1951
Louis, Joe, 1914-1981.
851698 AA, Aa 2, UAm
Champion prize fighter of Detroit, Michigan. Scrapbooks, 1935-1941 (arranged chronologically by bout), and clippings, articles, and fan letters, 1948-1951, relating to his career as a boxer.
93 volumes
0.2 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mr. John W. Roxborough (donor no. 4033 ) and came to the library in 1963.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Joe Louis was born in Lexington, Alabama on May 13, 1914. With his family, he later moved to Detroit, Michigan, where he became a professional prize fighter, winning championships as an amateur, then as a professional. He was heavyweight champion of the world from 1937 to 1949. Some of his more memorable bouts were with Primo Carnera in 1935, with Max Schmeling in 1936 and 1938, and with James J. Braddock in 1937. He died April 12, 1981.
The scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings and magazine articles in the period of 1935-1941. The volumes include full-length articles, brief sketches, cartoons and newspaper photographs detailing each fight, the preliminaries, Louis' opponent, the bout itself, and post-fight assessments. The volumes are numbered 1-94; volume 48 was not received.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Athletics--United States.; Boxing.; Detroit (Mich.); Louis, Joe, 1914-1981.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Boxing.; Braddock, Jim.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Louis, Joe, 1914-1981.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.
Genre Terms:
Cartoons.; Paintings.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks (arranged by date and name of Joe Louis' opponent)
  - 1935
    - Vol. 1, Primo Carnera (Volume 1)
    - Vol. 2, Primo Carnera (Volume 2)
    - Vol. 3, King Levinsky (Volume 3)
    - Vol. 4, King Levinsky/Max Baer (Volume 4)
    - Vol. 5, Max Baer (Volume 5)
    - Vol. 6, Max Baer (Volume 6)
    - Vol. 7, Max Baer (Volume 7)
    - Vol. 8, Max Baer (Volume 8)
    - Vol. 9, Max Baer (Volume 9)
    - Vol. 10, Paulino Uzcudun (Volume 10)
    - Vol. 11, Paulino Uzcudun (Volume 11)
    - Vol. 12, Paulino Uzcudun (Volume 12)
  - 1936
    - Vol. 13, Paulino Uzcudun (Volume 13)
    - Vol. 14, Paulino Uzcudun (Volume 14)
    - Vol. 15, Chas. Retzlaff (Volume 15)
    - Vol. 16, Chas. Retzlaff (Volume 16)
    - Vol. 17, Chas. Retzlaff (Volume 17)
    - Vol. 18, Max Schmeling (Volume 18)
    - Vol. 19, Max Schmeling (Volume 19)
    - Vol. 20, Max Schmeling (Volume 20)
    - Vol. 21, Max Schmeling (Volume 21)
    - Vol. 22, Max Schmeling (Volume 22)
    - Vol. 23, Max Schmeling (Volume 23)
    - Vol. 24, Max Schmeling (Volume 24)
    - Vol. 25, Max Schmeling (Volume 25)
    - Vol. 26, Jack Sharkey (Volume 26)
    - Vol. 27, Jack Sharkey (Volume 27)
    - Vol. 28, Al Ettore (Volume 28)
  - 1937
    - Vol. 29, Jorge Brescia (Volume 29)
    - Vol. 30, Eddie Simms (Volume 30)
    - Vol. 31, Bob Pastor (Volume 31)
    - Vol. 32, Natie Brown (Volume 32)
    - Vol. 33, James J. Braddock (Volume 33)
    - Vol. 34, James J. Braddock (Volume 34)
    - Vol. 35, James J. Braddock (Volume 35)
    - Vol. 36, James J. Braddock (Volume 36)
    - Vol. 37, James J. Braddock (Volume 37)
    - Vol. 38, James J. Braddock (Volume 38)
    - Vol. 39, James J. Braddock (Volume 39)
    - Vol. 40, James J. Braddock (Volume 40)
    - Vol. 41, James J. Braddock (Volume 41)
    - Vol. 42, James J. Braddock (Volume 42)
    - Vol. 43, Tommy Farr (Volume 43)
    - Vol. 44, Tommy Farr (Volume 44)
    - Vol. 45, Tommy Farr (Volume 45)
    - Vol. 46, Tommy Farr (Volume 46)
  - 1938
    - Vol. 47, Tommy Farr (Volume 47)
    - Vol. 48 (Volume 48)
      (volume not received)
    - Vol. 49, Nathan Mann (Volume 49)
    - Vol. 50, Harry Thomas (Volume 50)
    - Vol. 51, Max Schmeling (Volume 51)
    - Vol. 52, Max Schmeling (Volume 52)
    - Vol. 53, Max Schmeling (Volume 53)
    - Vol. 54, Max Schmeling (Volume 54)
    - Vol. 55, Max Schmeling (Volume 55)
    - Vol. 56, Max Schmeling (Volume 56)
    - Vol. 57, Max Schmeling (Volume 57)
  - 1939
    - Vol. 58, Max Schmeling (Volume 58)
    - Vol. 59, John Henry Lewis (Volume 59)
    - Vol. 60, John Henry Lewis (Volume 60)
    - Vol. 61, John Henry Lewis (Volume 61)
    - Vol. 62, John Henry Lewis (Volume 62)
    - Vol. 63, Jack Roper (Volume 63)
    - Vol. 64, Jack Roper (Volume 64)
    - Vol. 65, Tony Galento (Volume 65)
    - Vol. 66, Tony Galento (Volume 66)
    - Vol. 67, Tony Galento (Volume 67)
    - Vol. 68, Tony Galento (Volume 68)
    - Vol. 69, Tony Galento (Volume 69)
  - 1940
    - Vol. 70, Bob Pastor (Volume 70)
    - Vol. 71, Bob Pastor (Volume 71)
    - Vol. 72, Arturo Godoy (Volume 72)
    - Vol. 73, Arturo Godoy (Volume 73)
    - Vol. 74, Arturo Godoy (Volume 74)
    - Vol. 75, Johnny Paycheck (Volume 75)
    - Vol. 76, Johnny Paycheck (Volume 76)
    - Vol. 77, Arturo Godoy (Volume 77)
    - Vol. 78, Arturo Godoy (Volume 78)
    - Vol. 79, Arturo Godoy (Volume 79)
    - Vol. 80, Arturo Godoy (Volume 80)
    - Vol. 81, Arturo Godoy (Volume 81)
  - 1941
    - Vol. 82, Al McCoy (Volume 82)
    - Vol. 83, Al McCoy (Volume 83)
    - Vol. 84, Red Burman (Volume 84)
    - Vol. 85, Gus Dorazio (Volume 85)
    - Vol. 86, Abe Simon (Volume 86)
    - Vol. 87, Tony Musto (Volume 87)
    - Vol. 88, Buddy Baer (Volume 88)
    - Vol. 89, Buddy Baer (Volume 89)
    - Vol. 90, Billy Conn (Volume 90)
    - Vol. 91, Billy Conn (Volume 91)
    - Vol. 92, Lou Nova (Volume 92)
    - Vol. 93, Lou Nova (Volume 93)
    - Vol. 94, Lou Nova (Volume 94)
- Other materials
  - Loose clippings, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs and other visual materials (Box 1)
    (see also oversize folder UAm)
Related Material
The Smithsonian Institute has a similar set of scrapbooks assembled by another Louis manager, Julian Black.